<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiona Horner</title>
    <link>https://fionahorner.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fiona Horner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fionahorner.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick Code: Bootstrapping</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/quick-code-bootstrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/quick-code-bootstrapping/</guid>
      <description>The boot package in R makes bootstrapping easy – but the format of the output is somewhat of a nightmare. Here, I talk through a small function to extract your boot confidence intervals in a more user-friendly format. If you are new to functions, this could be a good example to get a feel for how they work.
library(boot) library(tidyverse) Let’s say we have some sample data of N = 200.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restructuring Data for Intensive Longitudinal Analysis</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/restructure-ild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/restructure-ild/</guid>
      <description>I’ve manually restructured data for intensive longitudinal analyses one too many times… So I wrote a function to do this for me, and posted here so I’d remembered that I had done so.
Specifically, this code parses intensive longitudinal data (ILD, e.g., daily diary, EMA) variables into within-person and between-person components. Between-person variables are grand-mean centered averages; i.e., an individual’s average score across the ILD period centered around the total sample mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Multilevel Data: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/simulating-multilevel-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/simulating-multilevel-data/</guid>
      <description>Here, I show how to simulate multilevel data, specifically intensive longitudinal (daily diary) data. Multilevel data poses some challenges for simulation because it violates assumptions of independence and analyses typically include estimation of random effects (e.g., each person may have their own intercept and slope). This tutorial assumes background knowledge of multilevel modeling and within- and between-person effects.
Once you understand how to simulate multilevel data, you can see how to incorporate it into power simulations here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Multilevel Data Part 2: Dependent Predictors</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/dependent-predictors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/dependent-predictors/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, I show how to simulate multilevel (daily diary) data when you have dependent predictors that are divided into within- and between-person components. Just like in part 1, we’ll pull our parameters from an existing dataset and model for ease. But keep in mind that in many cases (like power analyses), you may need to pull these parameters from pilot data or from the literature.
I’ll base my simulation on the same data and model used in part 1, so I recommend reading that post first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variance Component Analysis</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/variance-component-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/variance-component-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Variance component analysis (VCA) is a way to assess the reliability of measures designed for intensive longitudinal data, like daily diary or ecological momentary assessment studies. This type of study poses particular challenges when it comes to measurement, because you need your measure to accurate capture your construct of interest, but to do so in a way that is sensitive to small changes over short periods of time. That is, you are explicitly interested in capturing these within-person changes in a reliable way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>Download _______________________________________ Education _____________________________________________ Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA PhD in Social/Personality and Health Psychology Expected 2025 Advisor: Vicki Helgeson, PhD
Northwestern University, Chicago, IL Post-Baccalaureate Certificate in PsychologySeptember 2019 Weinberg College of Arts and Sciences
Colorado College, Colorado Springs, CO Bachelor of Arts, cum laude May 2015 Major in Anthropology; Minor in Religion
Research Interests _____________________________________________ Adjustment to diabetes, diabetes outcomes, digital health, psychosocial predictors of disease outcomes, stress, positive affect, close relationships, interpersonal coping</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/cv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/cv2/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIH NRSA (F31) Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/nihfellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/nihfellowship/</guid>
      <description>_______________________________________ Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>_______________________________________ Selected Publications View my complete publication list on my CV or Google Scholar.
Helgeson, V.S., Horner, F. S., Reis, H., Niezink, N. M. D., Libman, I. (2024) Peer interactions and health among youth with diabetes: An ecological momentary assessment. Health Psychology. 43(9), 684–693. https://doi.org/10.1037/hea0001393 Download
Horner, F.S., Helgeson, V. (2023). Effects of Positive Affect and Stress on HbA1c: A Prospective Longitudinal Study. Journal of Behavioral Medicine, 1-11. Download</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Resources</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/rresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/rresources/</guid>
      <description>I started graduate school knowing absolutely nothing about R. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s my primary language and comfort zone. Below are a some of my favorite resources that helped me develop my R programming skills:
Best for the basics: Read these start to finish R Programming for Data Science by Roger D. Peng Stat 545 by Jenny Bryan
Best all around reference: R for Data Science by Hadley Wickham and Garrett Grolemund</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/resume/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
