<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiona Horner</title>
    <link>https://fionahorner.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fiona Horner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fionahorner.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick Code: Bootstrapping</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/quick-code-bootstrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/quick-code-bootstrapping/</guid>
      <description>The boot package in R makes bootstrapping easy – but the format of the output is somewhat of a nightmare. Here, I talk through a small function to extract your boot confidence intervals in a more user-friendly format. If you are new to functions, this could be a good example to get a feel for how they work.
library(boot) library(tidyverse) Let’s say we have some sample data of N = 200.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Multilevel Data: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/simulating-multilevel-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/simulating-multilevel-data/</guid>
      <description>Here, I show how to simulate multilevel data, specifically intensive longitudinal (daily diary) data. Multilevel data poses some challenges for simulation because it violates assumptions of independence and analyses typically include estimation of random effects (e.g., each person may have their own intercept and slope). This tutorial assumes background knowledge of multilevel modeling and within- and between-person effects.
Once you understand how to simulate multilevel data, you can see how to incorporate it into power simulations here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Multilevel Data Part 2: Dependent Predictors</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/dependent-predictors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/r-demos/dependent-predictors/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, I show how to simulate multilevel (daily diary) data when you have dependent predictors that are divided into within- and between-person components. Just like in part 1, we’ll pull our parameters from an existing dataset and model for ease. But keep in mind that in many cases (like power analyses), you may need to pull these parameters from pilot data or from the literature.
I’ll base my simulation on the same data and model used in part 1, so I recommend reading that post first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>[Download](/files/FH_CV_2022.pdf) _______________________________________ Education _____________________________________________ Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA PhD in Social/Personality and Health Psychology Expected 2025 Advisor: Vicki Helgeson, PhD
Northwestern University, Chicago, IL Post-Baccalaureate Certificate in PsychologySeptember 2019 Weinberg College of Arts and Sciences
Colorado College, Colorado Springs, CO Bachelor of Arts, cum laude May 2015 Major in Anthropology; Minor in Religion Honors Thesis: Practice and Community at Compassionate Dharma Cloud Monastery
Research Interests _____________________________________________ Coping with chronic illness, psychosocial predictors of health, diabetes, positive affect, close relationships, stress, interpersonal coping, cancer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Resources</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/rresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/rresources/</guid>
      <description>I started graduate school knowing absolutely nothing about R. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s my primary language and comfort zone. Below are a some of my favorite resources that helped me develop my R programming skills:
Best for the basics: Read these start to finish R Programming for Data Science by Roger D. Peng Stat 545 by Jenny Bryan
Best all around reference: R for Data Science by Hadley Wickham and Garrett Grolemund</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://fionahorner.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fionahorner.com/research/</guid>
      <description>_______________________________________ I am interested in how close relationships, positive affect, and stress impact coping and health outcomes, and am particularly interested in exploring these questions in the context of chronic illnesses like diabetes and cancer. More recently, I have focused on the role of time-varying psychosocial factors, like mood and stress, in predicting blood glucose and health behaviors throughout the day among people with diabetes. I use intensive longitudinal data collected from ecological momentary assessments and digital health devices, like continuous glucose monitors (CGMs) to answer these questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
